MARIA C. RUPNER

979 SW 147th Avenue, Pembroke Pines, FL 33027

954 895 3359 crupner@gmail.com

PROFILE

Creative **Human Resources Executive** known for attracting and retaining talent by aligning compensation with business management systems and designing compensation strategies to improve performance. Highly analytical with ability to draw conclusions, themes, and trends from data analysis, communicate results, and influence decisions at highest level. Areas of expertise:

- Employee Relations
- Diversity and inclusion
- Performance Management
- Talent Mapping
- Compensation

- Staffing (all levels including Executive)
- Benefits programs
- Training and Development
- Succession Planning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GIBRALTAR PRIVATE BANK & TRUST, Coral Gables, Florida

2001 - 2018

Executive Vice President, Human Resources Director

Provided day-to-day direction and leadership on all aspects of human resources function to key operating executives and business units of a \$2 billion financial institution. Served as a member of the executive team which developed and executed strategies to promote organizational success. Oversaw staffing, compensation and benefits, performance management, legal compliance and succession planning.

- In partnership with other business unit leaders, ensured that the organization had the people systems in place and strategically aligned to support the bank's operating controls, administrative and operating procedures in order to ensure attainment of operating efficiencies and objectives.
- Worked closely with management at all levels as well as employees to promote and maintain a collaborative environment, build employee morale and increase productivity and retention.
- Continuously review, update and disseminate HR related policies.
- Responsible for designing and communicating human capital metrics and human resources initiatives to Executive Management and the Board of Directors, in order to identify trends and aid in the short and long-term planning and decision process.
- Managed recruiting process and procedures to ensure speed, efficiency, and effectiveness of the overall recruiting process. On-boarded staff at all levels within stringent deadlines.
- Developed and implemented compensation process and procedures that resulted in equitable pay programs that were easily tracked and cost effective.
- Designed and implemented a performance management process to promote performance excellence and address deficiencies in accordance with company policy.
- Designed, executed and tracked job specific and compliance training.
- Managed employee relations, including all legal and regulatory matters.
- Led communication, benefits, systems, and human capital transition for two mergers.

GIBRALTAR BANK, Coral Gables, Florida

1996 - 2001

Assistant Vice President, Executive Assistant to EVP/COO, Recording Secretary to the Board of Directors and Shareholder Liaison

Provided support to Executive Vice President and Chief Operating Officer with focus on areas such as reporting, Board of Directors information and compensation, Shareholder communication and records. Initially supported and then oversaw Human Resources Manager.

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS

Associate of Arts, Business Administration – Briarcliffe College – Miami, FL Paralegal Certification – Briarcliffe College – Miami FL

Completed SHMR's SPHR Certification Curriculum

Trained with executive level HR professional in all areas of HR - 2000 - 2003

PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

Society for Human Resources Management (SHRM)

SIGNIFICANT PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Developed a dedicated and professional HR Team that served as a partner to Executive and Senior Management to aid in ensuring the bank met its strategic objectives.
- Designed and implemented a formalized On-boarding process and New Hire Orientation.
- Enhanced benefit's package resulting in a competitive overall compensation package which improved talent attraction and retention.
- Designed, implemented and maintained a performance management process that resulted in higher accountability, measurement of performance against goals, performance improvement plans, etc. Designed, implemented and trained managers on a formalized disciplinary action process.
- Assessed training needs throughout the organization; designed and implemented a two-prong training program which included online training as well as leader led training for managers and associates.
- Created and implemented the Associate Development Program which consisted in developing
 recent graduates into bankers with on the job training as well as classroom training and
 mentoring. The program yielded several graduates.
- Created the Shadowing Program which resulted in improved collaboration between associates, departments, and business units by breaking down silos. It also served as a platform for career pathing.
- Initiated an internship program which yielded at least one hire per season for every year that the program was in place.
- In partnership with CEO, led a Mission, Vision and Values initiative to promote company culture, collaboration and understanding of the company's strategic goals and objectives, thereby creating a line of sight from each associate, to the company's strategic goals.
- Led various Executive Retreats which included team building exercises and team member assessments, designed to enhance team work, collaboration and communication. It involved, amongst others, brain storming sessions focused on company direction and strategy.